Daniel Walder

Computer Engineering & Cognitive Science

Contact

Address

Unit C, 4046 Mahaila Ave La Jolla, 92122

Phone

(619) 629-5735

E-mail

dwalder@ucsd.edu

GitHub

Waldibaldi123

LinkedIn

daniel-walder-ucsd

Education

University of California

- San Diego

B.S.: Computer Engineering Minor in Cognitive Science GPA 3.8

About me

Certified Assistant Judo Instructor

Pianist and Ballroom Dancer

Native German speaker

3rd year Computer Engineering & Cognitive Science student at University of California – San Diego. Worked on embedded systems responsible for vital functions of \$200,000 rocket. Performed large-scale data analysis forwarded to the Austrian government.

Work History

2019-07 -2019-08

ISHAP CARD, Vienna, Austria

Analyst Intern

- Invented own predictive risk model to identify scammer companies
- Wrote Python/PHP that automatically visualized 200+ Austrian companies
- Findings presented to clients and Federal Ministry of Finance

2018-09 -2019-06

Rocket Propulsion Laboratory, La Jolla, CA

Avionics Software Engineer

- Implemented self-engineered communication protocols in Java/C
- Communicated ideas to 40+ team members and thoroughly documented all work for base11 competition
- Rocket estimated at \$200,000 and team ranked 4th place nationally

2018-01 -2018-07

Austrian Military, Horn, Austria

Paramedic

Projects

2020-06 -Current

Trumpagotchi iOS-App

- Recruited and worked with artists and political science researchers in the US and Austria
- Large-scale project focused on scalability and design patterns specific to videogames
- Documented on www.trumpagotchi.website

Other:

Online Rock-Paper-Scissors android-app with accounts and matchmaking

8-Bit Breadboard Computer

built with 40+ ICs and 12 breadboards